RG 047, Special Tax Commission
Connecticut State Library
Special Tax Commission records
1932-1935
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Special Tax Commission
10.5 cubic feet
By Special Act 474, approved June 9, 1933, the General Assembly formed the “Temporary Commission to Study the Tax Laws of the State and to Make Recommendations concerning their Revision,” which quickly took the name, “Special Tax Commission.”
RG047
Multiple
Historical Note
By Special Act 474, approved June 9, 1933, the General Assembly formed the “Temporary Commission to Study the Tax Laws of the State and to Make Recommendations concerning their Revision,” which quickly took the name, “Special Tax Commission.” It consisted of seven appointed members headed by Professor Fred R. Fairchild, and a small research staff directed by Benjamin P. Whitaker. The Commission held six public hearings and obtained assistance from private citizens and state government officials. It submitted a report to Governor Wilbur Cross on November 9, 1934. The first was a 94 - page summary followed by a full report of 642 pages.
Scope and Content
Includes minutes, correspondence, administrative papers, papers on fiscal year change study, publicity material and a general file.
Related Material
RG 045, State Revenue Task Force, 1969 - 1971
RG 077, Bipartisan Commission on State Tax Revenue and Related Fiscal Policy, 1982-1983
RG 086, Governor's Commission on Tax Reform, 1972
RG 087, Connecticut Tax Study Commission, 1966 - 1967
Connecticut. Special Tax Commission. Summary of the report of the Connecticut temporary commission to study the tax laws of the state & to make recommendations concerning their revision. Hartford, 1934.
[CSL call number T19sp/rs].
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Special Tax Commission
Persons:
Fairchild, Fred R.; Whitaker, Benjamin P.
Subjects:
Connecticut. Special Tax Commission -- Records and correspondence; Taxation -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Clippings; Correspondence; Memorandums; Minutes; Notes; Payroll records; Press releases; Purchase orders; Requisitions; Vouchers
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1932-1935
  - 1. Minutes of meetings, 1933 June 23-1935 February 19; T002709 (Box 1)
    At the beginning is a subject index to the minutes up to June 26, 1934.
  - 2. Correspondence of the Research Director and the staff, 1933-1935
    - With Commission members (Box 2)
      Arranged alphabetically by name.
    - With others (Box 3)
  - 3. Correspondence of the Chairman, 1933-1935 (Box 3-4)
    A substantial part consists of correspondence with the Research Director. The first folder contains lists of memoranda prepared by research staff and agenda of meetings.
    Unarranged.
  - 4. Administrative papers, 1933-1935 (Box 5)
    Status of appropriation reports, statements of expenditures, requisitions on stores, payrolls, expense vouchers, purchase orders and related documents and correspondence.
  - 5. Papers on fiscal year change study, 1932-1933
    Following the suggestion, as a relief measure that all towns have the same fiscal year beginning 1 July, a study was made by Judge S. Russell Mink to determine the effects on tax collection, payment of interest, etc. The papers of the study, evidently carried on from the Office of the Tax Commissioner, were apparently turned over to the Special Tax Commission.
    Arranged in two groups, each alphetical by town, preceded by general material and followed by pages from printed statutes concerning town fiscal affiars (marked "Outs").
    - General (Box 6)
    - Ansonia-Hartford (Box 6)
    - Meriden-Putnam (Box 7)
    - Rockville-Willimantic (Box 8)
    - Andover-Portland (Box 9)
    - Preston-Woodstock (Box 10)
    - "Outs" (Box 10)
  - 6. Publicity materual, 1933-1935 (Box 11)
    Press releases, clippings and related material.
  - 7. General file, 1933-1935
    This appears to be a consolidation of several working files, containing research memoranda, collected reference material, working papers, drafts, notes and correspondence.
    - General (Box 12)
      With agenda, calendar of hearings, etc.
    - "Memoranda" (Box 12)
      Incomplete set.
    - Government revenues and expenditures (Box 13)
    - Municipal finances (Box 14)
    - Taxes on:
      - Amusements (Box 15)
      - Banks (Box 15)
      - Billboards (Box 15)
      - Business (Box 15)
      - Highways (Box 16)
      - Incomes (Box 16)
      - Inheritance and estates (Box 16)
      - Insurance (Box 16)
      - Intangible personal property (Box 17)
      - Interest and dividends (Box 17)
      - Liquor (Box 17)
      - Miscellaneous taxes (Box 17)
      - Motor vehicles (Box 17)
      - Personal tax (Box 17)
      - Property taxes (Box 18)
      - Public utilities (Box 19)
      - Real estate (Box 19)
      - Sales (Box 19)
      - Transportation and communications (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 20)
- Report, 1934; 1999-115
  - Connecticut. Special Tax Commission. Report of the Connecticut temporary commission to study the tax laws of the state & to make recommendations concerning their revision as provided by Special Act no. 474 of 1933 & submitted to the Governor of Connecticut, November 9, 1934. Hartford, 1934. 2 volumes. (Box 1)